So, here is another trick that will help us move a point closer to a line,
这里是另一个技巧 可以帮助我们让某个点更加接近直线
and is very similar to the Absolute Trick,
这与绝对值技巧非常类似
but it has a little bit of extra grading.
不过有些特别之处
It is based on the premise,
它有个前提
if we have a point that is close to a line,
如果我们这个点靠近直线
then this distance is small,
距离较小
and we want to move the line very little.
我们想小幅移动直线
But if the point is far from the line,
但是如果这个点远离直线
then we want to move the line a lot more.
我们想大幅移动直线
The absolute trick that we'll learned previously does not
我们之前学过的绝对值技巧
have this property because if we remember,
不具有这个属性 因为如果还记得的 话
the absolute trick adds alpha to the y-intercept W2 and p times alpha to the slope W1.
绝对值技巧将 α 加到 y 轴截距 W2 中 p 乘以 α 加到斜率 W1 中
This has nothing to do with how far the point is from
这与点到直线的距离无关
the line since p is just the horizontal distance.
因为 p 只是水平距离
So let's just add the vertical distance to this formula.
所以现在我们把垂直距离加到这个公式中
Let's look at this vertical distance between the point and the line.
我们来看一下 这是点到直线的垂直距离
The distance is q minus y,
距离为 q 减去 y
because y is the value of the line and q is the value of the y-coordinate at the point.
因为 y 是直线的值 q 是这个点的纵坐标值
So what we do here is very simple.
所以我们这里要做的很简单
We just take this q minus y and multiply it into what we
我们用这个 q 减去 y 的结果乘以
are adding to both the y-intercept and to the slope.
我们加入 y 轴截距和斜率的值
This will again make the line go up by a bit and rotate in
这样可以再让直线向上移动一点
the direction except that now if the point is far from or close to the line,
沿着方向旋转一些 如果这个点距离直线过远或很近
the amount the line moves will be affected.
直线移动的数量会受到影响
And here's our new equation with a factor of q minus y.
因此我们在新的方程中包含一个因数  q - y
Notice that here, we get something for free.
注意下这里 我们很容易得到了想要的东西
If the point is underneath the line instead of over the line,
如果这个点在直线的下方 而不是上方
then q minus y is actually a negative value.
那么 q - y 实际上是负数
And if this is the case, then we're subtracting something from the slope,
如果是这种情况 我们在斜率中减去某个数
thus rotating the line in this direction instead still towards the point.
然后沿着这个方向旋转直线 而不是向这个点旋转
So this trick also takes care of points that are under the line
所以这个技巧也考虑到点位于直线下方的情况
and we don't have to have two rules like we had on the absolute trick.
我们可以不用像绝对值技巧一样使用两个规则
We just have one rule for both.
可以一石二鸟
And again, let's clarify this with an example.
我们再通过例子来详细了解下
In this example over here,
在这个例子中
we have the point 5,15.
这个点坐标为 (5,15)
And notice that this distance is going to be two because the line goes to
注意此处距离为 2 因为
the point 5,13 as two times five plus three, is 13.
2*5+3 等于 13 所以直线上的这个点为 (5,13)
Now, to change things a bit,
现在稍微改变一下
we'll use 0.01 as our learning rate.
我们设学习率为 0.01
So with the absolute trick, we'd be adding 0.01 to the y-intercept and 0.05 to the slope.
利用绝对值技巧 我们在 y 轴截距加 0.01 在斜率加 0.05
But now, as our new trick sets,
但是现在根据新技巧
we multiply the two numbers that we're adding to the slope and to the y-intercept by two,
我们用加在斜率和 y 轴截距的两个数字乘以 2
which means we're adding 0.1 to the slope and 0.02 to the y-intercept.
也就是说我们在斜率加 0.1 在 y 轴截距加 0.02
So the equation of our new line is Y equals 2.1X plus
所以我们的新方程为 y = 2.1x + 3.02
3.02 and that line is going to be closer to the point.
这条直线更加靠近这个点
So that's it. That's the Square Trick.
就是这样 这叫做平方技巧